<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>statnet on Social Ecological Networks Group</title>
    <link>https://seng.netlify.app/tags/statnet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in statnet on Social Ecological Networks Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://seng.netlify.app/tags/statnet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exponential Random Graph Models, An Introduction</title>
      <link>https://seng.netlify.app/2022/10/19/exponential-random-graph-models-an-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seng.netlify.app/2022/10/19/exponential-random-graph-models-an-introduction/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionWe can a learn a lot about a network using visualization tools and descriptive statistics. But many researchers would like to make inferences about how specific variables influence the probability of a network connection. There are multiple ways to do this – latent network modeling, multilevel Bayesian models, quadratic assignment procedures – but one of the most common and versatile methods is to build Exponential Random Graph Models (ERGMs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Simulation using {statnet}</title>
      <link>https://seng.netlify.app/meetings/introduction-to-network-simulation-with-statnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seng.netlify.app/meetings/introduction-to-network-simulation-with-statnet/</guid>
      <description>PreambleIn this post, I will demonstrate how to use tools from the statnet collection of packages to simulate and model networks. The purpose of this post is to provide readers with tools that I wish I had when I first started using network analysis. I’m not an expert and I’m still learning how to use these tools well. But knowing they exist and how to use them will enable you to creatively study network processes and validate your prior knowledge of and conclusions about the networks that you study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Networks in R</title>
      <link>https://seng.netlify.app/meetings/introduction-to-networks-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seng.netlify.app/meetings/introduction-to-networks-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Data StructuresThe Square MatrixThe EdgelistBut Why?Bernouli Graph SimulationNetwork objects in igraphMatrix \(\rightarrow\) networkEdgelist \(\rightarrow\) networkVisualize igraph objectsNetwork objects in statnetVisualize network objectsReferencesIn this meeting, we cover the basics of working with networks in R. By the end of the workshop, you will be acquainted with three packages – igraph, statnet, and tidygraph – and you will be able to create a network from scratch, turn it into a network object, create vertex and edge attributes, and genereate a basic visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
