<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>simulation on Social Ecological Networks Group</title>
    <link>https://seng.netlify.app/tags/simulation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in simulation on Social Ecological Networks Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://seng.netlify.app/tags/simulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Network Visualization Techniques</title>
      <link>https://seng.netlify.app/2023/02/12/advanced-network-visualization-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seng.netlify.app/2023/02/12/advanced-network-visualization-techniques/</guid>
      <description>Picture this: You’re working on project and you’ve just finished collecting all your network data. You’ve worked hard to get a complete network and you’re eager to start analyzing it. You power up your computer, load up Rstudio, and after lots of careful wrangling and tidying, you’re ready to plot the network. With great anticipation, you write a little code and WHAM! you get hit with a hot plate of spaghetti and meatballs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Egocentric patterns in homophilous networks</title>
      <link>https://seng.netlify.app/meetings/complete-and-egocentric-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seng.netlify.app/meetings/complete-and-egocentric-networks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Researchers who work with smaller populations that have clearly defined boundaries (Laumann, Marsden, and Prensky 1989) may be able to design survey instruments that can feasibly document an entire social network. These complete, sociocentric networks can exhibit some systematic biases (Ready et al. 2020), but they typically do a better job of characterizing the full suite of direct and indirect connections within a population.
Many researchers, however, work in larger populations that have fuzzy boundaries, if any.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network size and structure</title>
      <link>https://seng.netlify.app/2021/12/22/size-structure-and-density/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seng.netlify.app/2021/12/22/size-structure-and-density/</guid>
      <description>The size of a network is determined by the number of vertices and edges within it, and different size networks have different structural properties. This is obviously true if social processes like homophily, preferential attachment, or triadic closure influence network size, but it is also true for randomly generated networks.
How do properties like density, sparseness, degree distribution, or connectivity change as the number of vertices in a network increases?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Simulation using {statnet}</title>
      <link>https://seng.netlify.app/meetings/introduction-to-network-simulation-with-statnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seng.netlify.app/meetings/introduction-to-network-simulation-with-statnet/</guid>
      <description>PreambleIn this post, I will demonstrate how to use tools from the statnet collection of packages to simulate and model networks. The purpose of this post is to provide readers with tools that I wish I had when I first started using network analysis. I’m not an expert and I’m still learning how to use these tools well. But knowing they exist and how to use them will enable you to creatively study network processes and validate your prior knowledge of and conclusions about the networks that you study.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
