<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>igraph on Social Ecological Networks Group</title>
    <link>https://seng.netlify.app/tags/igraph/</link>
    <description>Recent content in igraph on Social Ecological Networks Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://seng.netlify.app/tags/igraph/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An introduction to community detection and network motifs</title>
      <link>https://seng.netlify.app/2022/12/06/community-detection-and-subgraph-patterns-in-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seng.netlify.app/2022/12/06/community-detection-and-subgraph-patterns-in-networks/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will focus on two topics: community detection and subgraph motifs. In previous posts, we have discussed some basic methods for describing network structure. We used these methods to either describe the positioning of individual nodes (e.g., centrality metrics) or some global properties of a network (e.g., connectivity, average path length). Now we will focus on subgraph patterns that transcend the scale of individuals or dyads but nevertheless reside within a global network of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Re)Introduction to Networks in R</title>
      <link>https://seng.netlify.app/meetings/re-introduction-to-networks-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seng.netlify.app/meetings/re-introduction-to-networks-in-r/</guid>
      <description>In this meeting, we cover the basics of working with networks in R. By the end of the workshop, you will be acquainted with three packages – igraph, statnet, and tidygraph – and you will be able to create a network from scratch, turn it into a network object, create vertex and edge attributes, and genereate a basic visualization. Let’s get started.
R Markdown IntroductionBefore we begin talking about networks, let’s first talk about the R studio environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Networks in R</title>
      <link>https://seng.netlify.app/meetings/introduction-to-networks-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seng.netlify.app/meetings/introduction-to-networks-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Data StructuresThe Square MatrixThe EdgelistBut Why?Bernouli Graph SimulationNetwork objects in igraphMatrix \(\rightarrow\) networkEdgelist \(\rightarrow\) networkVisualize igraph objectsNetwork objects in statnetVisualize network objectsReferencesIn this meeting, we cover the basics of working with networks in R. By the end of the workshop, you will be acquainted with three packages – igraph, statnet, and tidygraph – and you will be able to create a network from scratch, turn it into a network object, create vertex and edge attributes, and genereate a basic visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
